SEAN STICKLAND

ICT Technician Turned Full Stack Software Developer

STICKLANDSM@GMAIL.COM • 021 829 780 • NZ CITIZEN

HTTPS://WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/SEAN-STICKLAND-AA26461AB/

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/STICKLANDSM

HTTPS://WWW.PORTFOLIO.SANDCASTLEINK.NZ/

ABOUT ME

I have 4 years of experience working in software companies as an ICT Technician with a keen interest in coding. More recently, I have made a full-time transition to software development. In May, I successfully completed the coding bootcamp, Dev Academy Actearoa, where I excelled in my studies.

The bootcamp aims to simulate real agile development teams. Due to my coding aptitude and prior experience, I often assumed the role of team lead. I scoped out the projects, ensured progress was being made, and provided guidance whenever others were blocked. I then used my evenings to work on coding the back ends. I emerged as one of the most proficient students in my cohort.

Combining my extensive industry experience in the IT world, with my enthusiasm for software development, I am an ideal candidate for a software development team.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

- Proficient in coding with TypeScript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS among others.
- Experienced in using Git and GitHub, code reviews, and RESTful API services.
- At Dev Academy, I demonstrated the ability to quickly grasp new concepts and technologies, which allowed me to excel in my coursework.
- Previous experience as an ICT Technician for both a world-renowned software company, Vista Entertainment, and other smaller companies provides a unique understanding of the software business.
- Developed automation scripts to streamline ICT tasks and increase efficiency.

EXPERIENCE

Dev Academy | Jan 2023 – May 2023 | Student

- Gained experience in using modern web development tools and techniques, while also focusing on essential human skills such as providing feedback, collaboration, and working in agile teams.
- For my final project, I led a team in creating a restaurant ordering app, where I took charge of coding the back-end and much of the front-end.
- I made extensive unit tests for the app to ensure that it met the highest standards of functionality and user experience. This experience allowed me to showcase my skills in both technical development and leadership.
- See the app here: https://waitless.sandcastleink.nz/table/1/menu

Tekne LTD | Dec 2020 - Dec 2022 |

ICT Technician

- Developed strong organizational and communication skills to effectively manage the IT needs of small and large businesses across NZ.
- Collaborated with team members and clients to solve complex IT challenges, which further developed problem-solving skills and built stronger relationships.
- Demonstrated ability to rapidly adapt to new clients, environments, and systems, expanding knowledge and skills with ease.

Vista Entertainment | Apr 2019 - Nov 2020 |

ICT Technician

- Stayed up to date with industry trends and best practices to improve system performance and security, effectively managing risks.
- Developed initial coding skills by writing automation scripts to expedite computer setup processes, gaining experience in scripting and automation.
- Collaborated with developers to resolve routine hardware and software issues, further developing my technical and problem-solving skills.

Sony Mobile, Oceania | Feb 2015 - Dec 2018 |

Service Warranty & Training Manager

Managed staff training, repairs, refunds, and dealt with tribunal cases against Sony.

Sony Electronics, Oceania | Oct 2013 - May 2015 |

Customer Support Representative, IT Specialist

Customer facing consumer support for VAIO laptops.

EDUCATION

2023 - Dev Academy Aotearoa

■ Certificate in Applied Software Development

2010 - Auckland University of Technology

Certificate in Computer & Mathematical Sciences

This included courses on Java programming and calculus

ACHIEVEMENTS

During my graduation ceremony at Dev Academy, my teacher applauded my aptitude for programming and leadership.

In recognition of my exceptional work at Sony Mobile, I was sent to Sweden to talk at their annual training conference.

PERSONAL

In my spare time, apart from coding silly word games, I enjoy playing guitar badly, watching terrible action movies with my friends, and seeing indie rock bands.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.